Brendan Joseph O'Connor

E-MAIL sp.brendan@gmail.com

PHONE +254721714848, +353871091420 LINKEDIN <u>linkedin.com/in/oconnorbrendan</u>

PORTFOLIO pandaboy.github.com

P.O. BOX 54717-00200 NAIROBI, KENYA

Software Engineer with experience designing, developing and working with game platforms, large complex systems, web platforms and integrating with third-party platforms and infrastructure. I have experience working in and leading teams of other developers and professionals.

Work Experience

Boilerhouse Digital: Co-Founder (2014-present) - boilerhouse.digital

- API design and implementation
- Web application development (Backend/Frontend)
- Mobile application development
- DevOps

M-Farm Ltd: Senior API Developer (2013-2014) - mfarm.co.ke

- API Design and implementation
- Web application development
- Mobile application development
- SMS integration
- DevOps

Squad Digital/OgilvyOne (Scangroup): Developer (2012 - 2013)- squaddigital.com

- Website and Application development for clients including:
 - Safaricom
 - o <u>Airtel</u> (including: Airtel Ghana, Airtel DRC, Airtel Kenya, Airtel Gabon)
 - o <u>Tecno Mobile</u>
 - o <u>Standard Chartered</u>
 - o <u>GoDown</u> Art Center/<u>Nai ni Who</u> Campaign
 - o NACADA
- Technology Research including:
 - Unity Game Engine
 - Microsoft Surface
 - o Microsoft Kinect
 - o Leap Motion
 - o Android apps
 - o Semantic Analysis
- Integration with 3rd party systems including those from: Facebook, Google, Instagram, Twitter, JamiQ and Safaricom
- Systems design and development for internal projects
- HTML/Testing support

Openworld Ltd: Senior Developer (2010 - 2012) - openworld.co.ke

• Systems design and development for clients including:

- Kenyan Government (Performance Contracting Department)
- African Union (AU-IBAR)
- Integration with 3rd party systems including but not limited to:
 - Oualtrics
 - o Google
- USSD/Mobile development (in Java)

JS Engine: Senior Developer (Apr - Nov 2010) - jsengine.net

- Website development and interface design for clients including but not limited to:
 - United Nations (UNDESA)
 - o XYZ Show
 - o TinTin Restaurant

Consulting work Clients include, but not limited to:

- Samchi Credit: <u>samchicredit.co.ke</u>
- <u>AU-IBAR</u> (African Union InterAfrican Bureau for Animal Resources)
- UNDESA (United Nations Department for Economic and Social Affairs)
- CREA Africa: <u>creaafrica.com</u>
- EOS Solar: eos.co.ke
- Mara Moja Transport: <u>maramoja.co.ke</u>

Other Ventures

• Boilerhouse Digital: boilerhouse.digital

Covered: <u>getcovered.co.ke</u>METRIK: <u>metrik.co.ke</u>

Education

1. MSc Computer Science (Interactive Entertainment Technology) at Trinity College Dublin (2014 - 2015)

 $Graduated\ with\ Upper\ Second\ Class\ Honours\ (2:1)$

2. Bachelor of Business and Information Technology (BBIT) at Strathmore University (2006 - 2010)

Graduated with Upper Second Class Honours (2:1)

References

1. Joe Njeru Murithi

Chief Executive Officer at Zilojo Limited

Tel: +254722787725

2. Dr. Sam Gakunga

Director, Corporate Risk Services, P.O. BOX 19754-00202 Nairobi Kenya

Tel: +254720632330